Hello everyone!
In the 2024.1 version, the virtual model editor has been optimized.
Adjusting the size is more intuitive and accurate, and it can adjust the shape of the model chest and chest and other specific parts.
Let's take a closer look.
First, with the update of the virtual model editor, we added a new default virtual model, which is more suitable for the virtual model editor after the update.
In the virtual model editor window, you can see the new default model name, the model name is v2.1, and the model name is v1.1.
Other virtual models can be found in the Connect store.
Open the old version of the virtual model editor here.
In the main menu, find the virtual model editor.
Open the virtual model editor.
At this time, you can see that if you use the virtual model editor to open it,
or the one that was previously created in the 2024.1 version,
the AVS file will be imported to the new virtual model editor.
In the virtual model editor, a warning window will pop up.
This is because the size data of the new virtual model editor has changed.
Therefore, the model body shape may change according to the size data of the update.
So, when creating a virtual model, you need to pay attention to this.
Now, the virtual model editor after the update is divided into two aspects, size and shape.
In this section, you can choose to preset the size and modify the unit.
In the previous version, the size content related to the details of the whole body is all included here.
In the previous version, you can choose the simple, basic, high-end human body or human body model in the details.
Each type of size project that can be entered and modified is different.
After optimization, the UI mountain goes to the basic and high-end model options.
You can freely choose and enter the required size project.
Click on the gear icon in the upper right corner to display the editable measurement value.
At this time, all editable measurement values will appear at the bottom.
You can choose the measurement value of the size you need below.
The size that is selected and displayed in blue is the size that can be edited.
The unselected project will not be displayed when editing and cannot be adjusted directly.
But it will automatically adjust to the appropriate size according to the input value in the existing measurement size.
After selection,
click on the exit button in the upper right corner to complete the settings.
You can see that only the project we just selected is in the display and editable state under the size.
In addition, in the previous version, the model size of the virtual model was adjusted based on the algorithm.
This means that when you modify the height, shoulder height, chest and other full body sizes,
it will create the appropriate body shape according to the algorithm and the data you input.
We have added the function of individually modifying each size project.
This function is expressed by the link icon on the right side of the width and height.
If you want to modify the virtual model in the same way as before,
you can click on the icon and activate it to modify the virtual model size.
You can see that the size below is automatically adjusted with the adjustment of the width and height value.
On the contrary, if you click on the icon and cancel the connection again,
you can change the width and height value.
For example, the chest and height below will remain unchanged.
If you want to modify the model height in the same size preset, you can use this function.
The new version can also modify the size of the cup.
First, select the chest size in the width and enter the value,
then enter the chest size below.
You can see that the chest is fixed and the cup size will change.
In this way, you can create a virtual model of different cup sizes.
The following shapes include the adjustment of the arm length,
the adjustment of the head circumference and the new width adjustment.
For men, you can also adjust the volume of the waist.
In the previous version, the waist of the model is not adjustable.
This may cause simulation problems when creating tight clothing, such as swimsuits and underwear.
Now you can freely adjust the waist of the model,
so that it is more convenient to make swimsuits, underwear and other clothes.
Next, you can see the virtual model of the 3D window on the left side.
Previously, the measurement line position on the virtual model was fixed and unable to be modified.
In the new version, we added a virtual model that can move the measurement line function.
You can drag and drag the measurement line position directly to adjust the size of the virtual model.
First of all, when you open the window of the virtual model editor,
the default will automatically start the virtual model measurement tool.
Use this tool to drag and drag the actual line on the model to measure.
You can see that the selected measurement line is displayed in yellow.
And there will be a virtual arrow at the top and bottom of the moving process middle line.
These arrows indicate the maximum range of the measurement line that can be moved.
In order to avoid exceeding the range of the selected measurement line,
you can move the measurement line to the desired position.
Or overlap with other measurement lines.
The range of movement of the measurement line is limited to three centimeters above and below.
After moving the measurement line to the desired position,
modify the corresponding size at the window of the virtual model editor on the right side.
You can check the effect of the modification at the 3D window.
If you want to restore the original position,
you can right-click on the measurement line to reset the position or reset all positions.
This is the update and improvement content of the virtual model editor function in the 2024.1 version.
I hope that you can create a virtual model that satisfies you more easily and accurately by using these functions.